

Personal Info

Software Engineer / Android Developer

Contact:

Phone: +98(914)492-1058 Telegram: @msamrd

Email:

mousamk@gmail.com

Age:

30 years old

Current Location:

Tehran, Iran

Preferred Work location:

Anywhere

MOUSA MORADI

Software Engineer

About me

I am a passionate and motivated software engineer with more than 10 years of experience. I have experiences in different areas, like Web, Desktop and Mobile app development, however, my current career and specialty is mainly Android development.

I am very adaptable and can quickly learn and use new technologies, languages and concepts. I deliver high quality software and clean code. I am a team worker and can communicate and cooperate well with other team members.

Work experience

شيپور | Sheypoor

*Android Developer*January 2019 – Present

Sheypoor provides classified advertisements website and mobile apps for goods and services. I am a member of the mobile applications development team in Sheypoor and participate in their development. The main Android app is installed and used by more than 1 million users.

تخفيفان | Takhfifan

Android Developer April 2016 – November 2018

Takhfifan is a Groupon-like company based in Iran and it's the leading in Iranian market. I developed and maintained its Android apps. <u>One of them</u> has more than 500,000 users.

پکتوس | Pactos

Symbian/Andoird Developer August 2011 – March 2016 I developed some mobile apps in this company which targeted blind users, including: a full-featured text/audio book player, input method (IME) by sketch, Persian text-to-speech and a few more. All of them were developed at first for Symbian OS and then for Android. I also developed a native Driver for their Braille monitor in C language for Android.

Sharif University of Technology

Web Developer / System Admin September 2014 – March 2016

As part of my mandatory service for the country, I worked in this university and maintained its main website and sub-websites. I also developed a separate website for new students registration process.

Earlier experiences

June 2010 – August 2014 Web/Desktop/Mobile/Embedded Developer

I had a few other experiences including desktop app development with C#, iOS development with Objective-C and Swift, embedded apps development with C/C++, and etc.

Skills

I am expert in these languages, technologies, frameworks, and concepts:

Object Oriented Design and Development, Design Patterns, Architectural Patterns, Functional Programming, Reactive Programming, Test Driven Development, Java, Kotlin, C++, Android framework, Qt framework, SQL, MySQL/MariaDB, SQLite, UML, git, Linux OS, Scrum

Android Specific: RxKotlin, Retrofit, Volley, Picasso, MVVM, MVP, RIBs, Realm DB, Dagger, JUnit, Espresso, Mockito

I have intermediate level of expertise or familiarity with these languages and technologies:

PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Swift, Objective C, Python, Ruby, Rails, C#, GraphQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Android Specific: Material Design, Room, Koin, Data Binding

Education

- <u>Sharif University of Technology</u>. Iran Master of Software Engineering, 2011-2013 (Sharif University is the top one university of Iran and 5th of Middle East)
- Sharif University of Technology. Iran Bachelor of Software Engineering, 2006-2011

Language Skills

English Fluent
Persian Native
Azerbaijani Native
Esperanto Fluent
Turkish Intermediate

German Basic

Honors & Awards

- Ranked among 0.001 top participants of national university entrance exam. (Rank 406 out of 500K) 2006
- Ranked among 0.001 top participants of national graduate university entrance exam. (Rank 10 out of 10K) 2011

Links

- <u>Stackoverflow</u>
- <u>Linkedin</u>
- <u>Github</u>
- Personal website